Naeem Ali

Address: Unit-603 850 Canterbury Ave, Ottawa, ON, K1G3B1. Email: Naeem.nizarali@gmail.com Phone: +1 306-209-9939 Portfolio: https://mystifying-mahavira-4cc2dc.netlify.app/

Summary

Motivated retail professional with strong sales, customer service and problem-solving abilities. Skilled at selling Product or Service and able to learn new information quickly to maximize contributions and respond to changing customer preferences. Desire to apply expertise and make lasting positive impact on business operations.

Skills

Sales (Customer care, Communications, Customer service & Problem resolution)
Graphic Design (Digital graphics, Corporate branding & Print Design)
Web Design / Development (HTML5, CSS3, Java Script, Jquery, UI / UX Design)
Technical Skills (Adobe Creative Suite (Photoshop, Illustrator, In Design, and XD),
Microsoft Office (Word, Excel, Power Point)

Work Experiences

Best Buy (Nov 2019 – March 2020) Mobile and Smart Living Advisor Prince Albert, SK

Consulted with customers to understand exactly what their needs were and provided tailored recommendations and solutions. Provide customer support to Visage customers, responding to inquiries relating to mobile device activation, configuration and service issues and Installation. Engaged positively with each customer, providing professional and polite support for sales and service needs. Restocked shelves, racks and bins with latest merchandise and changed signage to promote special items. Maintained current store, product and promotional knowledge to drive consistent sales. Stocked shelves and supplies and organized displays to focus customer attention on specific items. Processed payments and maintained accurate drawers to meet financial targets.

National Hotel / Liquor Store (May 2016 – Feb 2020) Store Supervisor Prince Albert, SK

Inspired customers to try new items by educating on wines and store promotions. Reviewed driver's licenses and other forms of ID to ensure proof-of-age, refusing sales to anyone under 21. Kept till neat and accurate and secured large bills in safe to minimize losses from theft. Took payment for purchases by cash, credit, debit and personal check and provided the correct change. Maintained thorough and current knowledge of available

brands and lines to give customers expert advice. Minimized product loss with proper rotation and handling of bottles, cans and cases. Cleaned and restocked aisles through shifts to maintain customer-ready store. Complied with strict liquor sales laws to control store liability and protect minors from access to alcohol. Answered questions from callers and in-store guests to offer information and promote products. Resolved issues with cash registers, card scanners and printers. Counted drawers at start and end of shifts to validate daily records and uphold accounting accuracy.

OPA! Greece Food (Oct 2015 – April 2016)

Cook Helper

Regina, SK

Organized ingredients and restocked supplies to prepare for busy periods.

Packaged and stored food products appropriately to ensure proper handling and preservation.

Monitored and recorded temperatures of food, storage, and service areas to maintain established, regulatory guidelines. Maintained clean and sanitized work area in accordance with food safety guidelines, avoiding cross-contamination of raw and prepared food products. Stored perishable food items in freezer or refrigerator to protect food from spoilage.

Axact Pvt Ltd (Nov 2009 – May 2015)

Senior Graphic Designer

Karachi, Pakistan

Oversaw work of junior designers, keeping team members working within established deadlines. Wrote precise specifications for printing and reproduction for printing vendors. Enhanced design process by offering multiple solutions in conceptual models, layout and typography. Managed multiple design tasks with short deadlines by prioritizing job responsibilities, overseeing deadlines and monitoring all tasks. Enhanced existing designs with new layouts, graphics and content. Designed mockups and wireframes utilizing graphics software skills. Developed creative, graphic presentations to communicate mood, emphasis and insight. Created corporate brands by designing cohesive looks between logos and letterheads. Developed website layouts, templates and unique branded looks for more than 100+ projects.

Education

University of Regina (Sep 2015 – April 2016) Diploma in Business Administration Regina, SK

Karachi School of Arts (Sep 2005 – Dec 2009) Diploma in Communication Design Karachi Pakistan

Voluntary Services

Al-Azhar Garden Student Association

Teacher: Adobe Photoshop Adobe Illustrator

Rahimabad Scout Unit

Scout Member

References

Available upon request